Hey everyone, Tasha Keany. I'm here with
Daniel Maguire and today we're going to
talk about our updates to our embodied
AI and space research for our big ideas
report to start with robo taxis. So
Daniel, talk us through this graph.
>> Uh really what this graph uh represents
is just uh one of the rationale behind
why robo taxis are starting to
proliferate around the United States. So
today uh in the US, Whimo really leads
the way as it relates to a commercial
robo taxi service. They're completing
over 500,000 driverless uh weekly rides
uh with the intention of scaling that to
1 million driverless rides per week. Uh
and we believe that is uh largely thanks
to the safety of robo taxi. So uh
following Whimo's disclosures, we
believe that Whimo's operations are now
safer than uh the average national
accident rate in the United States. Uh
when you look at what Whimo reports on
police reported uh crashes relative to
the average in the US. Um and really
that just goes to show uh the importance
of robo taxi proliferating. Not only uh
is it a lot more comfortable uh it also
has the intention and uh possibility of
saving a lot of the thousands of lives
that are lost in the United States as it
relates to vehicle crashes. Um but re
really uh that's kind of specific to
Whimo. taking a step back at the US land
landscape. Tasha, um when when you look
at Tesla, they are really starting to
scale their robo taxi operations. They
are operating now in seven different
regions. Uh I personally tested the
service in Tampa last week and it was
really a seamless experience. I'd
encourage everyone to test it if it's in
your local region. We always say seeing
is believing. Um and this comes at a
time when Tesla is rolling their cyber
cab off the production line. So this is
their purpose-built robo taxi with no
steering wheel, no pedal, no wing
mirror. Um, and it's really an exciting
time in the US for robo taxi as Whimo,
Tesla, others like Zuks are are really
starting to to compete.
>> Yes. So to put it in context, why do we
care um that robo taxis have crossed
this threshold? Um well, you know,
Whimo's in 14 cities now, Tesla's in
seven cities operating robo taxi
service. Um and this year was a great
expansion year for both. I think Tesla
expanded to something like a handful of
cities, say five or so throughout the
year. Whimo added, I want to say nine
cities. Um and if you think of how
regulators look at this issue, it's
going to be quite important for them to
be able to prove that they're safer than
human drivers. Um this is of course uh a
big part of our thesis on robo taxis. We
think the ultimate driver of adoption
will be price that they can undercut um
human-driven ride hail prices and expand
the network. Um but of course safety is
paramount here. Few other things that
I'd like to talk about. In general, you
know, we choose to look at the national
average human accident rate. Many of the
robo taxi companies um have already
proved that on like a a physical injury
uh basis or if you drill down to sort of
specifics of the worst crashes, the ones
that actually harm us or uh you know do
a lot of damage. Um they're they're
already much much safer. Um but if you
just zoom out and look at uh national
average human accident rate, you know,
regardless of who's at fault, um I think
it's very important to to note that
they're also surpassing humans there.
Um, so robotex is already safer um than
than humans. Now it's just a matter of
how quickly will it take to scale and
expand the service. You know, Daniel
touched on a couple points here. Uh,
this year we got some positive signs
from regulators. Um, Zuk's got some
positive approvals recently. Uh, we saw
that um, you know, officials were saying
that they will allow cars without um,
pedals or steer steering wheels going
forward. That's important for cyber cab
production, of course. Um so there's a
lot of like green flags that we have in
the space here but uh you know we're
still early days in robo taxi expansion
and I I think this will this year and
next year will be a pivotal year uh to
really see that um take more share from
human driven radill.
>> Great and so a lot of the discussion we
we've just spoken about is really
specific to the United States. Uh but
but taking a step back there is also
robo taxis proliferating around the
world. So uh in China you have players
like BU we ride Pony AI all who are
starting to scale in China but what
we've really seen this year in the first
seven months of the year is a lot of
those Chinese players taking their
solutions from China where it's
extremely price sensitive market and
very cost competitive uh to markets such
as the Middle East and Europe where
there's a greater pricing umbrella. Uh
so you have the likes of Wii ride,
PonyAI uh as well as BYU who are
starting to proliferate around Europe.
Um and really what this this chart is
trying to demonstrate is the state of
affairs today. Uh and when you look at
fleets of robo taxis that are operating
and testing today, as we mentioned,
Whimo really is in the lead globally.
However, it's important to note the
point around autonomous capable
vehicles. Uh so Tasha, would you like to
explain to the viewers what what do we
mean by autonomous capable?
>> Sure. So, this is Tesla's suite of
customer cars that they use as little
mini R&D centers to collect information
to train the fleet and how to drive
better. Um, it's important to point out
because although Tesla's only in seven
cities, they actually have driving
information from really all over the
world, everywhere that you see Teslas
drive. Um and uh you know of course
better information I would say in in
areas where um full self-driving is
approved but um you know all Teslas are
equipped with cameras that track
accident data and collect information on
the specifics of the road they drive um
to help train the system. So this is a
unparalleled data advantage that they
have um that we think they can leverage
to scale their robo taxi fleet. Um and
and you know Daniel pointed out the
price difference uh just to elucidate
that a little better. You know in
western markets the average price of red
hill is two $2 uh per mile or above. Uh
you know in China that's 50 cents uh per
mile or or even lower. So um you know
there's quite a bit of of difference in
terms of pricing power um where these
these these companies operate. Even
though China is very progressive in
pursuing autonomous technology, um just
from an economic perspective, it'll be
harder for companies to make money
there. Uh so we're focused on the US,
we're focused on the western markets
where again there's just better uh
pricing dynamics. Okay. And now uh
moving on to autonomous logistics. Um
there's a lot to cover here. Uh many
different form factors that we think can
uh you know, we just talked about
transporting people. This is
transporting goods. this can be done
with robots of all shapes and sizes, but
we decided to focus on drones for this
update um because there's been so much
that's been happening in that in that
space. So, Daniel, take it away.
>> Yeah, sure. So, I think a risk of
stating the obvious, it's important to
state that autonomous logistics and
drone delivery is here today. Uh very
often we come across people who I think
it's a state of play in the future, but
it is operating today around the world.
Um and to talk about maybe some of the
updates we have seen since our big ideas
report at the beginning of this year. Um
firstly as you can see top of the chart
is zipline they recently surpassed 2.5
million cumulative autonomous
deliveries. Uh they are now starting to
scale their platform 2 drone which is a
smaller form factor than the platform
one where they operated in Africa making
a lot of deliveries for medical
purposes. uh this is a a different
solution that has a smaller uh baby
drone or a droid coming out uh really
targeting residential uh drone delivery.
Uh in addition then in the US Walmart is
a very large player here. They recently
announced over the last several weeks
that they have surpassed 1 million
autonomous drone deliveries that was
largely uh contributed by Zipline but
also Alphabet's wing subsidiary which is
their drone delivery solutions. Um
Walmart has uh very aggressive ambitions
here. So for context, by uh 2027,
they're hoping to be in 270 different
Walmart locations, giving them access to
over 40 million uh Americans. So for
those of you watching, if you don't have
access to Walmart drone delivery, I'm
sure it'll be uh on your doorstep uh in
the coming years. Uh this is also
against the broader backdrop in the
United States where competition is also
heating up. uh you have mana drone
delivery who is scaling its operations
that it started in Ireland and now
really focusing on the United States uh
but also some of the traditional
aggregators Tasha we saw last week uh
that uh Door Dash announced its in-house
drone delivery program and they also got
the FAA part certification 1235 which
enables them to operate airline like
services for drone deliveries. So really
it's it's starting to heat up in the
United States. You also have players in
the rest of the world like Maittoan and
China who are also scaling in the Middle
East. H and it's something that we're
really really watching closely. But
maybe Tasha if you want to add like why
do we care about drone delivery? What
will it do to unit economics and why
should customers care?
>> Sure. Um so Door Dash here if you look
at the um the average price that people
pay for food delivery in the US it's
about 30 bucks. About half of that is
the meal itself. The other half is fees
and other markups. Um, so there's
actually quite a high price ceiling.
People are actually paying double for
their food just to get it delivered for
the convenience of getting it delivered.
It's really um an amazing uh business
model that the Door Dash and others have
proven here. Um, so I think, you know,
very uh very notable that they are
choosing to verticalize here in drones
and start their own in-house effort. Um,
we're excited to see how that plays out.
And ultimately, we think that drone
delivery could lower the price of
delivery to say just around a dollar or
less or more likely it'll be looped into
the item that you're purchasing. So, you
won't you won't actually see it. It'll
just be uh, you know, in in the markup
that you see for the item itself. It'll
seem as if it's free, much like free
shipping happens today um, with Amazon
and others. Um although as I mentioned
Amazon you can notice it's at the bottom
of the graph here and they haven't made
as much progress in in drone delivery uh
you know considering their uh decade uh
decades old announcement in in the
space. Um so I I think it'll be an
exciting year to see see Dash and and
others uh compete in this market. All
right. Um we've talked about uh delivery
of people, delivery of goods. Uh now
we're moving on to robotics. Um sort of
a broader manufacturing focus. maybe
eventually home robots. Um but uh you
know if you look today at the fleets
that we have, this is the cumulative um
produced robots in different in various
categories. We're looking at humanoids
and quadripeds. Here you have roughly uh
you know 40,000 quadripeds, maybe 20,000
humanoids out there. Um there's likely
many more companies I should say that
that are not featured in these graphs
that exist. Um in China there I think
there are hundreds of of humanoid
manufacturers. Um but uh the the overall
picture here is uh we think the uh
capability of this technology um could
be very meaningful. We think that this
could be a 20 trillion plus market in
humanoids alone split between home
robots and manufacturing. Um but it is
just much earlier days than things like
uh autonomous driving. Autonomous
driving is a a defined um environment
where there's like rules of the road.
It's a arguably like a simple operating
environment, although we've we've
learned over the years that it's still a
very difficult problem to solve. Um,
humanoids just are a lot more complex.
You know, some of our past research has
estimated it's 200 thou,000 times more
complex um than solving for uh fully
autonomous driving here. So um it's a
it's a harder technology bar to pass and
uh it's also more difficult to collect
data because uh you can you know get
state approval to drive on public roads
and collect information on driving
whereas to get um manufacturing
information you know you need to be
located in the factory. You want to roam
the factory like kind of long before the
robot's capable of doing much. You want
to collect that information. Um so it's
just like a I would say a steeper hill
to climb there. Um, one other thing I'd
point out is that although many of these
robots exist, it's it's a different
question of like how many of them are
actually deployed and with customers. I
think that'll be the the interesting um
piece to look out for here in the
market. We see a lot of companies um
with with announcements of um how many
robots they've produced. I I think the
actual deployments are where you know
that's what really matters the
commercialization point. Um we see many
robots existing in China. One other
thing I'll point out in these graphs,
although uh you know we have seen that
the um technical ability of these robots
is still quite low. Um they they tend to
be dancing. They're um greeting people
in lobbies or um performing like uh like
vocal tasks sort of as you'd interact
with like a a chatbot sort of thing or
an LLM um versus the uh more difficult
complex like physical tasks that we
expect them to do in the future. Um so
and the supply chain actually needs to
be built out um as well for the for this
industry. Uh you know China is is
working on that. We've seen we've seen a
lot of news news out of um that country
but uh you know we know companies like
Tesla have talked about that this is
just an entirely new product so it's
going to be slower to scale. Um so you
know topline picture here we're very
excited about the opportunity 20
trillion plus. Um it's still an early
market and uh you know we love seeing
all the demo videos come out of of these
companies. figure just had a couple demo
videos that they they published
recently. Um, and what I think again
will be even more exciting is seeing
those deployments at customers.
>> Uh, last topic here, we've we've talked
about embodied AI. Let's talk about
something that will launch AI into
space. Daniel, reusable rockets.
>> Yeah. So, uh, it's been a very exciting,
uh, first half of the year for reusable
rockets. And it would be remiss of Tasha
and myself to sit here and not speak
about the SpaceX IPO which really
captured not only the space industry but
the overall public equity markets. Uh so
unless you've been living under a rock
but SpaceX h went IP or IPOed uh during
the year. Uh they IPOed at just less
than $2 trillion in value raising
roughly $85 billion of capital. Uh and
we've said this many times before that
we believe SpaceX has a 10-year lead on
the industry. They landed an orbital
class booster in 2015. The closest
competitor Jeff Bezos's Blue Origin
completed the same feat in 2025. And
since publishing Big Ideas, China has
also joined that exclusive group. So,
you know, well, why does that matter?
Well, rocket reusability really cuts
launch costs and opens up the space
economy, not only for SpaceX, but all of
the industry. Uh, and we estimate that
SpaceX has cut launch costs by roughly
95% since 2008. uh and that has really
opened up the space economy. Uh and
really what we're trying to demonstrate
with this updated chart since big ideas
is how dominant SpaceX has been. So if
you look at all active satellites in
Earth orbit today, SpaceX represents
roughly twothirds of all of those. Uh
that's thanks to its Starlink internet
connectivity service where its
constellation is growing weekly. It's uh
close to surpassing 11,000 active
satellites uh and provides a service to
over 12 million subscribers. So really
this is all enabled by declining launch
costs uh and was really a notable point
of SpaceX's uh IPO. Uh and then Tashi,
you mentioned about uh launching AI to
space. Really uh another critical point
of SpaceX's IPO and its S1 was orbital
data centers uh or as since they've
rebranded to uh Star Mind as they call
the AI satellites. Uh and it the SpaceX
identified a 28.5 trillion total
addressable market. Over 90% of that
relates to AI. Um and really that was
underpinning the whole IPO story. Uh and
in our big ideas we we mentioned uh
orbital data centers and how Starship
thanks to full and rapid reusability was
critical for unlocking that market. Um
but what we're trying to show here with
the second chart is uh upmass to orbit.
So at the beginning of the year we uh
demonstrated the amount of upmass that
has historically been sent to uh orbit
in 2025. that just uh surpassed uh 3,000
tons, metric tons. Um however, since big
ideas, SpaceX as part of its intentions
to launch a million satellites to uh
orbit supporting its AI ambitions has
provided a projection of how much up
mass it intends to send. Uh and by 2032,
SpaceX intends to launch in that year uh
roughly 1,000 times not percent 1,000
times more upmass than 2025 uh the
industry sent. So that's over uh just
approaching two and a half million tons
orbit. So these figures are are crazy.
As you can see with the animation, the
initial historical estimates aren't
visible on the second chart just to show
how ambitious SpaceX are as it relates
to their AI initiative. Um, and then
maybe lastly, Tasha, if you'd like to
speak about maybe the growing constraint
we see in the launch market uh as some
of the teaser SpaceX had as part of
their S1 relating to the future of the
Falcon 9.
>> Yes. Um, so you know, as Daniel
mentioned, SpaceX is lowering launch
costs. That opens up opportunities for
many space companies. Um, but in the
launch category specifically, uh, with
the focus on Starship, um, they are, uh,
discontinuing, we've seen that they've
discontinued the ride share program for
Falcon 9. Um, they're really opening up
that category for other launch companies
to come in. Um, so SpaceX will dominate,
will likely continue to dominate, um, in
terms of UPMASS. Um, but they will focus
more on the Starship program which just
has uh much higher payload capacity than
say the medium uh would you say Daniel
medium to small launch capacity
category.
>> Correct. Yeah. Um and really from Mark's
perspective it it highlights the
importance of vertical integration. Uh
there's some satellite providers now who
are really struggling to get access to
launch in the 2828 2029 plus time frame.
Uh so that's why like players like
SpaceX or uh Rocket Lab who uh recently
announced its intention to acquire
Aridium Communications uh owning not
only just the launch but also the
payload that's going into it is is
really important as access to launch
becomes uh increasingly tight following
uh the Blue Origin explosion in May of
this year. So re really that's kind of
all of the update for reusable rockets.
It's uh really exciting and something
that we monitor very very closely and uh
going forward for the rest of the year.
We're going to play pay very close
attention to the development of
Starship. That's critical to the SpaceX
thesis and really underpins the whole AI
story as part of its IPO.
>> Great. So continue to follow us on X and
look out for more research from us and
our big ideas presentation next year.
Thanks everyone.